The Drain
[Music]
Hey Nolik, come help me!
The fan and the computer needs that.
Not right now! Me and Tom Thomas
are painting a card for his parents' anniversary.
Oh! Look at you, you must be so tired!
Hi Simka! It's really great you're here.
I have a question. 12th anniversary —
is it spelled with an F or is it with a V?
Uh, you know what, first put down the number 12,
and then put a dash on there, and then a th.
on there and then a th oh right but first i'll change the water i'll be right back
oh mama left her in here
whoa oh no what have i done i spoiled my mom and dad's special day where in the bathroom
My mom's ring was lying there,
and I dropped it into the sink, and now it's washed away.
There goes the day!
It didn't wash anywhere!
Don't you know anything about how a drain trap works?
About a what?
A drain trap is a special curved pipe under the sink basin.
Water flows out of the faucet and flows down into the drain trap,
and after that it goes down to the sewer.
But when you turn off the water, not all of it washes away.
Some of it stays down in the drain trap.
It's made that way so the smell from the sewer won't get back into the house.
A ring is much heavier than water,
so if you happen to drop it down the drain, it won't wash away.
It will stay at the bottom of the drain trap.
Well, that means we still got a chance!
Yeah, but how in the world can we get it out of that trap?
Who knows?
I don't know how to swim.
Don't worry, it's all under control.
Do you have any thread?
Plenty of it.
Go get it and I'll be back in a flash!
I can't fix it like this.
I need my welder.
Papus!
I need to borrow your pack-o-mat for a little while.
Now that's a coincidence! I need to use it too!
Masiya, then I need to use your pack-o-mat!
What?
I'll bring it right back!
Hey! Where are you going?
Just watch what you're doing, dear!
Just like the name says, Fixies live to help machines and appliances.
But machines are very big and Fixies are very small,
so they can't get by without tools.
Long ago, Fixies worked with just about anything they could find.
Little feathers, threads, fins,
But now they have backpacks called pack-o-mats.
Inside a pack-o-mat are all sorts of tools.
Just push the button and the pack-o-mat spins around
quickly shooting out a hook, or a magnet, or even a parachute.
Every adult Fixie has their own pack-o-mat.
But before children can get them, they have to go to school and study hard,
and then pass an exam before they have the rights of a full-fledged Fixie.
And it's only after all of that that young Fixies get their own pack-o-mats.
And what? You're going down there with just that on?
Not just like this!
Like this?
Yeah, like that!
When I tug the thread, pull me up!
She was just saying,
when I tug on the thread, you need to pull me up!
I got it!
He just said,
I got it.
And I don't need to repeat what he says.
She said she doesn't need me to repeat what you say.
[Music]
Simka, Nolik, thank you. You really saved the day.
That's what Simka's for!
I said that's what Fixies are for!
Tom Thomas, who are you talking with in there?
Oh, your mom came back!
No one.
Hey, can you turn back into Fixies?
I've got to ask you a question.
I forgot. Should I write 12th anniversary with an F or do I write with a V?
Just write the number!
You're right!